Guide to the Phyllis Chesler Papers, 1968-2003 RL.00221
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Writings Series, 1969-1988 and undated
  - Mothers on Trial subseries, ca. 1979-1985 (Box W27)
    - Audiocassettes
      - L., Ilke, Aug. 7, 1981; commentary on M., Isabelle (Box W32)
      - L., Ilke, March 7, 1981 (Box W32)
      - M., Mary Terina (Box W32)
      - M., Mary, X., George, N., Georgia G., and R., Marjorie (Men -- Lost transcript) (Box W32)
      - M., Isabelle (Box W32)
      - McGovern, May 18, 1981 (Untranscribed Experts) (2 tapes) (Box W32)
      - M., Jan, and M., Fran, Aug. 10, 1981 (Box W32)
      - M., Jan, and G., Peter, Aug. 10, 1981 (Women -- Lost custody) (Box W32)
      - M., Sandra (Women -- Lost custody) (Box W32)
      - M., Lynn, Sept. 5, 1981 (Women -- Lost) (2 tapes) (Box W32)
      - Nadesha, Dec. 7, 1980 (Box W32)
      - NCW Family Law, July 13, 1981 (Experts) (Box W32)
      - Nurse -- WHW, Oct. 10, 1980 (Memos and Notes) (Box W32)
      - O, Jo, Dec. 19, 1980 (Women -- Gave up transcript) (Box W32)
      - P., Peggy -- lost June 6, 1981 (Box W32)
      - Phyllis -- novel, play, Oct. 12, 1980 (Medea) (Box W32)
      - Phyllis on analyzing interviews, Aug. 8, 1981 (Untranscribed Experts) (Box W32)
      - Phyllis/Medea/Sue -- play, Nov. 2, 1980 (Medea) (Box W32)
      - Phyllis/Sue, Oct. 12, 1980 (Medea) (2 tapes) (Box W32)
      - Phyllis/Susan, Oct. 8, 1980 (Medea) (Box W32)
      - P., Sarah, Sept. 14, 1981 (Women -- Lost) (Box W32)
      - P., Nancy, Aug. 19, 1981 (Untranscribed Experts) (2 tapes) (Box W32)
      - P., Jerry (Men -- Lost transcript) (Box W32)
      - P., Jerry -- 1973 Carter Advocate article/B., Don R., Doug, March 12, 1981 (Box W32)
      - R., Arlene -- WHW, Oct. 14, 1980 (Memos and Notes) (Box W32)
      - R., Janice, Nov. 7, 1981 (Memos and Notes) (2 tapes) (Box W32)
      - R., Janice, Nov. 7, 1981 (Women -- Won) (Box W32)
      - R., Michelle, April 21, 1981 (Box W32)
      - R., Patricia, July 17, 1981 (Women -- Lost) (Box W32)
      - R., Linda, Aug. 28, 1981 (Women -- Gave up transcript) (Box W32)
      - R., David, April 5, 1981 (2 tapes) (Men -- Won transcript) (Box W32)
      - R., Joanna WHW, May 21, 1981 (Memos and Notes) (Box W32)
      - S., Carolyn and S., Tobi, May 16, 1981 (Box W32)
      - S., Carolyn and S., Tobi, May 16, 1981 (Women -- Gave up transcript) (Box W32)
      - S., Jan. 3, 1982 (Women -- Won custody; transcribed, originals; Lynn B./B. -- W., Kay) (Box W32)
      - S., Dina, Feb. 21, 1981 (3 tapes) (Box W32)
      - S., Reen, Feb. 19, 1981 (Box W32)
      - S., Joanne, Aug. 5, 1981 (Experts) (Box W32)
      - Shelly -- WHW, Oct. 24, 1981 (Memos and Notes) (2 tapes) (Box W32)
      - S., Judith and R., Michelle, April 25, 1981 (Box W32)
      - S., Judith, April 24, 1981 (Box W32)
      - S., Naomi, June 29, 1981 (Women --Won) (2 tapes) (Box W32)
      - S., Edna, April 16, 1981 (Women -- Lost custody; trans original) (Box W32)
      - S., Jerry, Dec. 16, 1980 (Women -- Gave up transcript) (Box W32)
      - Some good women against women (Memos and Notes) (Box W32)
      - S., Alan, April 14, 1981 (Men -- Won transcript) (Box W32)
      - Susskind, Nov. 15, 1981 (Men -- Won transcript) (Box W32)
      - T., Sandi, (2 tapes) (Box W32)
      - T., Sandi, Nov. 22, 1980 (Box W32)
      - T., Jean, March 5, 1981 (Box W32)
      - V., Lucia, Jan. 10, 1981 (2 tapes) (Box W32)
      - V., Bruce, June 8, 1981 (Men -- Lost transcript) (2 tapes) (Box W32)
      - V., Mary Ann -- songs/do not erase (Box W32)
      - W., Maggie, Feb. 25, 1981 (Box W32)
      - W., Charlene -- Partially Transcribed March 13, 1981 (Box W32)
      - Wendy, May 14, 1981, D., Susan May 15, 1981 (Box W32)
      - W., John, July 9, 1981 (Men -- Won transcript) (Box W32)
      - W., Lillian, March 15, 1981 (2 tapes) (Box W32)
      - W., Lorri, July 9, 1981 (Experts) (Box W32)
    - Chapters (Box W33)
      Typescripts and manuscripts of chapters, filed in chapter order according to the published work.
      - Preface Sept., 1984 (Box W33)
      - Preface (2 folders) (Box W33)
      - Introduction Pieces (Discarded) (Box W33)
      - Chapter 1 (Summary) [Chapter 1] (Box W33)
      - Chapter 1: Phyllis' writings [Chapter 1] (Box W33)
      - Chapter 1: Custody [Chapter 1] (Box W33)
      - Chapter 2: The National Study [Chapter 2] (Box W33)
      - Chapter 11: Mothers Without Children [Chapter 3] (Box W33)
      - Chapter 3: Do "Good Enough" Mothers Still Lose Custody of their Children in North America Today? [Chapter 4] (Box W33)
      - Sexual Mother: (BSF) Sexual and Reproductive Rights [Chapter 5] (Box W33)
      - "Uppity Mother" Chapter 6 (Box W33)
      - Chapter 7 [Chapter 6] (Box W33)
      - Lesbian Mother (Proposals) [Chapter 7] (Box W33)
      - Poor Mother: Economics (My Proposals) [Chapter 8] (Box W33)
      - Married to Violent Men (Proposals) [Chapter 9] (Box W33)
      - Section 6: "Married to Violent Men" (BDF) [Chapter 9] (Box W33)
      - Section 7: "Married to Violent Men" (BDF) [Chapter 9] (Box W33)
      - Section 4: "Married to Violent Men" (Good Ind. Father) [Chapter 9] (Box W33)
      - 3A: "Married to Violent Men" (Bad Ind. Father) [Chapter 9] (Box W33)
      - 7. Male and Parenting [Chapter 12] (Box W33)
      - Male Domestic/Female Domestic [Chapter 12?] (Box W33)
      - Chapter 4: "Lawyers" April 29, 1983 [Chapter 13] (Box W33)
      - Chapter 14 [Chapter 17] (Box W33)
      - Intro. to Last Chapter [Part 5] (Box W33)
      - Last Chapter Proposals [Part 5] (Box W33)
      - Last Chapter: Domestic Violence [Part 5] (Box W33)
      - Last Chapter (2 folders) [Part 5] (Box W33)
      - Last Chapter (Carb.) [Part 5] (Box W33)
      - Last Chapter (Rough) [Part 5] (Box W33)
      - Last Chapter (Discarded) [Part 5] (Box W33)
      - LST carbon [Part 5] (Box W33)
      - Last: Working, Career, "Political Moms" Proposals [Part 5] (Box W33)
      - Last: Economics Text [Part 5] (Box W33)
      - LST Oct. 7 [Part 5] (Box W33)
      - LST Oct. 8 [Part 5] (Box W33)
      - LST Oct. 9 [Part 5] (Box W33)
      - LST Oct. 10 [Part 5] (Box W33)
      - LST Oct. 11 [Part 5] (Box W33)
      - LST Oct. 12 [Part 5] (Box W33)
      - LST Oct. 13 [Part 5] (Box W33)
      - Afterword (Box W33)
      - Footnotes (Box W33)
      - Footnotes: Economics (Box W33)
      - Custody, Footnotes (Box W33)
      - Appendix (Box W33)
      - "Note on Method" and Appendix (Box W33)
      - Women Hating Women and Cross Index (Box W33)
      - Legal Bibliography (Box W33)
  - Sacred Bond subseries, 1986-1988
    The Sacred Bond Subseries, 1986-1988, includes material for Chesler's 1987 book Sacred Bond: The Legacy of Baby M. Much of the material in this series documents Chesler's work with other feminist leaders as an activist in support of Baby M's birth mother, Mary Beth Whitehead. The Journal, Drafts, Class Transcripts, and Subject File sections within this subseries document the research, writing, and editorial process for Sacred Bond. The Trial Materials section contains materials documenting the custody battle for Baby M and the legal opinions of several organizations interested in the outcome of the case.
    - Journal, 1986-1987 (Box W34)
      Chesler's journal entries, phone logs, and chronologies of events surrounding the Baby M surrogacy custody trial. Materials chronicle her involvement with groups protesting in support of the rights of Baby M's birth mother, Mary Beth Whitehead. Much of the material in this subseries relates directly to the Journal Chapter in Sacred Bond. Arranged in chronological order.
      - 1986, Jan. 1 - 1987, Feb. 1, Diary Chronology (Box W34)
      - 1987, Jan. (Box W34)
      - 1986, Dec. 10 - 1987, Jan. 12, Phone Log (Box W34)
      - 1987, Feb. 4 (Box W34)
      - 1987, Feb. 11 (Box W34)
      - 1987, Feb. 12, Notes upon speaking with MBW (Box W34)
      - 1987, Feb. 21 (Box W34)
      - 1987, Feb., Diary chronology (Box W34)
      - 1987, Feb. (Box W34)
      - 1987, Feb., Diary by category (Box W34)
      - 1987, Feb., Three note books (Box W34)
      - 1987, Mar. 1-13, Daily Work (Box W34)
      - 1987, Mar., One Notebook (Box W34)
      - 1987, Mar., Diary Chronology (Box W34)
      - 1987, Mar., Diary by Category (Box W34)
      - 1987, Mar., Phone message log (Box W34)
      - 1987, Mar. - 1987, Apr., Phone message log (Box W34)
      - 1987, Apr. (Box W34)
      - 1987, Apr., - May, Phone message log (Box W34)
      - 1987, Apr. 28 (Box W34)
      - 1987, May 4 (Box W34)
      - 1987, May 5 (Box W34)
      - 1987, May 6 (Box W34)
      - 1987, May 15-17, Amy Dial transcript (Box W34)
      - 1987, May, One notebook (Box W34)
      - 1987, May - June, Phone message log (Box W34)
      - 1987, June (Box W34)
      - 1987, June, Phone messages (2 folders) (Box W34)
      - 1987, July, Diary entries (Box W34)
      - 1987, July, Recreated diary entries (Box W34)
    - Class Transcripts, 1987
      Transcripts of Chesler's lectures and in-class discussions from classes she taught during the Baby M trial. The issues covered in her classes include surrogacy, feminism, motherhood, and women's rights. Arranged chronologically.
      - 1987, February 11 (Box W34)
      - 1987, April 22 (Box W34)
      - 1987, April 27 (Box W34)
      - 1987, April 29 (Box W34)
      - 1987, May 3-4 (Box W34)
      - 1987, May 18 (Box W34)
    - Conferences, 1987
      Conferences attended by Chesler while involved in the Baby M trial and while researching Sacred Bond. Many were related to surrogacy and reproductive issues and were mentioned in the Journal Chapter of her book.
      - 1987, January, Florida (Box W34)
      - 1987, March 20, College of Staten Island (Box W34)
      - 1987, April 4, N.Y.U. (Box W34)
      - 1987, April 11, Eastern Conn. State University (Box W34)
      - 1987, April 23, Women with Special Mental Health Needs (Box W34)
      - 1987, May 2, Rutgers (Box W34)
      - 1987, May 4, Doral Inn Conf. Transcript (Box W34)
      - 1987, May 4, Info. From May 4th Conference (Box W34)
      - 1987, May 4, May 4th Conference - essays presented (Box W34)
      - 1987, May 4, Rutgers Reproductive Laws (Box W34)
      - 1987, June 6, Refuse and Resist (Box W34)
      - 1987, June 26, NWSA (Box W34)
      - Miscellaneous, undated (Box W34)
    - Trial Materials, 1986-1988 (Box W35)
      Trial briefs, including several amici curiae briefs filed in support of the rights of Mary Beth Whitehead; mental health reports filed by experts who testified during the custody trial as to Mary Beth Whitehead's suitability as a parent for Baby M; and copies of exhibits entered as evidence in the trial. The materials are arranged in alphabetical order using Chesler's folder titles.
      - American Adoption Congress - Amici Curiae Brief (Box W35)
      - Aronstein Critique - Judicial Wrongdoing (Box W35)
      - Briefs of Defendants - Miscellaneous (Box W35)
      - Cassidy Brief (2 folders) (Box W35)
      - Cassidy Brief Part 1 - Annotated (Box W35)
      - Cassidy Brief Part 2 - Annotated (Box W35)
      - Cassidy Supplemental Brief (Box W35)
      - Cassidy's Appeal Brief (Box W35)
      - Catholic League for Religious and Civil Rights - Amici Curiae Brief (Box W35)
      - Chronology of Case, Statement of Facts (Box W35)
      - Committee for Mother and Child Rights - Amici Curiae Appellate (Box W35)
      - Concerned Women for America et al. - Amici Curiae Brief (Box W35)
      - Debevois and Plimpton - Amici Curiae Brief for Appeal (Box W35)
      - Exhibit K - Surrogacy Contract (Box W35)
      - Exhibit L - Surrogate Parenting Agreement (Box W35)
      - Feminists - Amici Curiae Brief (Box W35)
      - Foundation on Economic Trends - Amici Curiae Brief (Box W35)
      - Gruten Institute - Amici Curiae Brief (Box W35)
      - Karcher brief for Visitation, 1987 April 10 (Box W35)
      - Lorrain Abraham's Brief (Box W35)
      - Lorrain Abraham's Brief - Analyzed by Alison Ward (Box W35)
      - MBW Mental Health Report - Brodzinsky (Box W35)
      - MBW Mental Health Report - Einwohner (Box W35)
      - MBW Mental Health Report - Judith Grief (Box W35)
      - MBW Mental Health Report - Schechter (Box W35)
      - Mental Health Experts for MBW - Levine (Box W35)
      - Mental Health Experts for MBW - Nickman (Box W35)
      - Mental Health Experts for MBW - Pannor (Box W35)
      - Mental Health Experts for MBW - Phyllis Silverman (Box W35)
      - Mental Health Experts for MBW - Sokoloff (Box W35)
      - National Center on Women and Family Law - Amici Curiae Brief (Box W35)
      - New Jersey Catholic Conference - Amici Curiae Brief (Box W35)
      - Odyssey Institute - Amici Curiae Brief (Box W35)
      - Probation Report (Box W35)
      - Resolve, Inc. - Amici Curiae Brief (Box W35)
      - Rutherford Institute - Amici Curiae Brief (Box W35)
      - Skoloff's Appeal Brief (Box W35)
      - Skoloff's Brief - Analyzed by Alison Ward (Box W35)
      - Superior Court of New Jersey - Custody Opinion (Box W35)
      - Transcripts/Depositions/Exhibits to Appeal (2 folders) (Box W36)
      - United Birth Parents, Inc. - Amici Curiae Brief (2 folders) (Box W36)
      - Women's Rights Litigation Clinic - Amici Curiae Brief (Box W36)
    - Trial Transcript, 1985-1988
      Bound transcript of the Hintz trial, a surrogacy custody trial taking place in Iowa at approximately the same time as the Baby M trial and appeal. Arranged chronologically.
      - 1985, June 4 (Box W36)
      - 1987, Feb. 3 (Box W36)
      - 1987, Aug. 10 (Box W36)
      - 1987, Aug. 11 (Box W36)
      - 1987, Aug. 12 (2 folders) (Box W36)
      - 1987, Aug. 12 (Box W36)
      - 1987, Aug. 13 (Box W36)
      - 1987, Aug. 14 (Box W36)
      - Trial Appendix Vol. 1, 1988 (Box W36)
      - Trial Appendix Vol. 2, 1988 (Box W36)
      - Trial Appendix Vol. 3, 1988 (Box W36)
    - Subject Files, 1986-1988 (Box W37)
      The materials in the subject files document Chesler's activism during the Baby M trial as well as the research performed for Sacred Bond. Issues covered in these files include adoption, surrogacy legislation, women's reproductive rights, and legal issues surrounding surrogacy. This section also contains many clippings documenting coverage of the Baby M trial and of other surrogacy and custody trials. The folders are arranged in alphabetical order primarily using Chesler's folder titles.
      - Adoption (Box W37)
      - Adoption, 1987 (Box W37)
      - Adoption: Baslin cites (Box W37)
      - Adoption: Child Abuse (Box W37)
      - Adoption: General, 1987 (Box W37)
      - Adoption: Mother's Rights, Barlin (Box W37)
      - Adoption: Organ Sales (Box W37)
      - Ads for Surrogate Mothers (Box W37)
      - Baby M Correspondence, 1987 (Box W37)
      - Baby M Supporters: Baby M Group (Box W37)
      - Baby M Supporters: Lois Gould (Box W37)
      - Baby M Supporter/ Volunteers (Box W37)
      - Barlin Research [Legal Research: Adoption and Child Abuse] (Box W37)
      - Bergen Record: Trial Coverage, 1986-1987 (Box W37)
      - Book Proposal: 1987, Apr. 16 (Box W37)
      - Brodsky Kidnapping (Box W37)
      - Cassidy Brief Summary (Box W37)
      - Cassidy Brief Summary (Box W37)
      - Cassidy Brief Summery (Box W37)
      - Child Abuse: Barlin Research (Box W37)
      - Child Abuse: Infanticide, 1987 (Box W37)
      - Child Abuse: M.O.T. Ch. III (Box W37)
      - Clippings: Miscellaneous, 1987 (Box W37)
      - Contracts (Box W37)
      - Contracts: Barlin Research (Box W37)
      - Correspondence/ Odds and Ends, 1987, March (Box W37)
      - Correspondence with MBW's lawyers, 1987, Feb. 9 (Box W37)
      - Custody, 1980-1984 (Box W37)
      - Custody (Box W37)
      - The Dark Side of Adoption, Marsha Riben manuscript (Box W37)
      - Debate with Noel Keare, 1987, April 1 (Box W37)
      - Demonstrations - Driving Directions (Box W37)
      - Demonstration - Hackensack, New Jersey, 1987, Feb. (Box W37)
      - Demonstration, 1987, March 4 (Box W37)
      - Demonstration, 1987, March 12 (Box W37)
      - Demonstration, 1987, March 31 (Box W37)
      - Demonstration, 1987, April 5 (Box W37)
      - Demonstration, 1987, April 10, MBW Vigil (Box W37)
      - Denson-Gerber Questionnaire (Box W37)
      - Dewanna Herman Banks (Box W37)
      - Diana Downs (Box W37)
      - Fathers and Child Rearing (Box W37)
      - Fathers Rights, 1987 (Box W37)
      - Fathers Rights: M.O.T. (Box W37)
      - Feminists on Surrogacy: Arditti, et. al. (Box W37)
      - Feminists on Surrogacy: K. Pollitt (Box W37)
      - Fetal Rights (Box W37)
      - Foster Care: Boarder Babies (Box W37)
      - Foster Care: Orphans, 1986-1987 (Box W37)
      - Happy Surrogate Mothers, 1987 (Box W37)
      - Harrison Critique of Trial, 1987, March 19 (Box W37)
      - Harrison Op. Ed. Piece, 1987, Feb. 18-22 (Box W37)
      - Hastings Center Washington Forum (Box W37)
      - In Vitro Fertilization (Box W37)
      - JDG Notes (Box W37)
      - Karcher, 1987 (Box W37)
      - Kidnapping: Paternal, 1987 (Box W38)
      - Lahey: In Progress (Box W38)
      - Lawsuits Against Surrogacy: Pimps, Contracts, Arrangements (Box W38)
      - Lecture Requests (Box W38)
      - Legislation: Lahey Reproductive Contracts Act (Box W38)
      - Legislation: Surrogacy Bills, California (Box W38)
      - Legislation: Surrogacy Bills, Connecticut- Tulisano (Box W38)
      - Legislation: Surrogacy Bills, Federal- Luken (Box W38)
      - Legislation: Surrogacy Bills, Hearing- "Alternative Reproduction Technologies" (Box W38)
      - Legislation: Surrogacy Bills, Michigan- Bansfield (Box W38)
      - Legislation: Surrogacy Bills, New Jersey- Arenstein Testimony (Box W38)
      - Legislation: Surrogacy Bills, New Jersey- Kern (Box W38)
      - Legislation: Surrogacy Bills, New York- Dunne/ Goodhue (Box W38)
      - Legislation: Surrogacy Bills, New York- Halipin Bill (Box W38)
      - Legislation: Surrogacy Bills, Pierce (Box W38)
      - Legislation: Surrogacy Bills, Washington, D.C.- Ray (Box W38)
      - Life Form Patenting (Box W38)
      - Male Parenting (Box W38)
      - Male Pregnancy, etc. (Box W38)
      - Media: Kempton, 1987 (Box W38)
      - Mental health portion of Appeal Brief, 1987, April 1-22 (Box W38)
      - Michigan ALCU: Surrogacy (Box W38)
      - Minor Points Checked for Legal (Box W38)
      - Miscellaneous (Box W38)
      - M., Pamela K. (Box W38)
      - Mothers Named in Ch. 2 (Box W38)
      - News Coverage of Trial, 1987, March 29 (Box W38)
      - News Coverage, 1987, April 10 (Box W38)
      - New York Times: Non-Trial Clippings (Box W38)
      - New York Times: Trial Coverage (Box W38)
      - New York Times: Trial Coverage (Box W38)
      - New York Times: Trial Coverage (Box W38)
      - Noel Keane (Box W38)
      - Noel Keane's Book (Box W38)
      - Notes (Box W38)
      - N.O.W.: All Resolutions (Box W38)
      - N.O.W.: Buffalo, 1988, June 24 (Box W38)
      - N.O.W.: Noreen Connel, 1987 (Box W38)
      - N.O.W.: Resolutions, 1988 (Box W38)
      - "Peter's Work" (Box W38)
      - Peter's Work Schedule (Box W38)
      - Peterson Case (Box W38)
      - Press Conference - Hackensack, New Jersey, 1987, Feb. 18 (Box W38)
      - Press Conference, 1988, Feb. 3 (Box W38)
      - Press Conference, 1988, June 6 (Box W38)
      - Reproduction (Box W38)
      - Reproductive Rights Press Conference - Kersten Salk's Speech, 1988, June 8 (Box W38)
      - Reproductive Rights Press Conference - Media Kits, 1988, June 8 (Box W38)
      - Reproductive Rights Press Conference - Miscellaneous, 1988, June 8 (Box W38)
      - Reproductive Rights Press Conference - Order of Speakers, 1988, June 8 (Box W38)
      - Reproductive Rights Press Conference - Participants Bios, 1988, June 8 (Box W38)
      - Reproductive Technology/Genetic Engineering, 1986-1989 (Box W38)
      - Rochelle Sharpe on Surrogacy Battles (Box W38)
      - Rosanne's Notes, 1987, June (Box W38)
      - Rothchild Paper: "Engineering Birth" (Box W38)
      - Siler Case (2 folders) (Box W39)
      - "60 Minutes" Etlin Case (Box W39)
      - Sorokow Decision Critique: Lea Stewart (Box W39)
      - Sorokow Decision Critique: Michelle Harrison (Box W39)
      - Sorokow Decision Critique: Richard Kruse (Box W39)
      - Sorokow's Decision, 1987, March 31 (Box W39)
      - Sperm Donors (Box W39)
      - Sperm Donors: M.O.T. (Box W39)
      - Statistics For Last Chapter (Box W39)
      - Supreme Court Decision (Box W39)
      - Supreme Court Decision: Annotated (Box W39)
      - Supreme Court Decision: Media, 1988, Feb 4 (Box W39)
      - Surrogacy (Box W39)
      - Surrogacy (Box W39)
      - Surrogacy Clinics (Box W39)
      - Surrogacy Contract: 1985, Feb 5 (Box W39)
      - Surrogacy Industry Overview (Box W39)
      - Surrogacy - Legal Analysis ACLU, Surrogacy Brief (Box W39)
      - Surrogacy - Legal Analysis Articles by Lawyers (Box W39)
      - Surrogacy - Legal Analysis, Avi Katz (Box W39)
      - Surrogacy - Legislation (Box W39)
      - Surrogacy - Media Analysis (Box W39)
      - Surrogacy - Media Analysis (Box W39)
      - Surrogacy - Research (Box W39)
      - Surrogate Parenting Agreement - Karcher (Box W39)
      - Trenton: 1987, Sept. 14 (Box W39)
      - Trial Clippings - Various Sources (Box W39)
      - Trial Clippings - Various Sources (Box W39)
      - Vicky W. (Box W39)
      - "We Are All Unfit" Letter, 1987, March 12 (Box W39)
      - Tuesday Whitehead's Letter to Baby "M," 1987, February (Box W39)
      - Women's Issues, 1987 (3 folders) (Box W39)
    - Drafts, 1987-1988 (Box W40)
      The Drafts document the writing, editorial, and publication process for Sacred Bond. Included are several early chapter drafts, one complete draft in chapter order, a proof copy of the manuscript, and fact checking materials. The folders are arranged in alphabetical order using Chesler's folder titles, except where an effort was made to keep chapter drafts arranged in chapter order.
      - Appendix (Box W40)
      - Chapter One (Box W40)
      - Chapter One - Introduction (2) (Box W40)
      - Chapter Two - Meditation, 1988, Jan. 19 (Box W40)
      - Chapter Three - History of Surrogacy (Box W40)
      - Chapter Four - Journal (3 folders) (Box W40)
      - Chapter Five - Contract and Contractions (Box W40)
      - Chapter Six - Last Chapter (Box W40)
      - Chapter Titles (Box W40)
      - Complete Draft - Chapter 1-2 - Introduction - Meditation (Box W40)
      - Complete Draft - Chapter 3 (Box W40)
      - Complete Draft - Chapter 4 - Journal (Box W40)
      - Complete Draft - Chapter 5 - Contracts and Contractions - (Box W40)
      - Complete Draft - Last Chapter (Box W40)
      - Copy Ed. Queries (Box W40)
      - Cover Design (Box W40)
      - Epilogue (Box W40)
      - Epilogue - Notes, Clippings (Box W40)
      - Fact Checking (3 folders) (Box W40)
      - Fact Checking -- Footnote, pg. 43 (Box W40)
      - Fact Checking -- Footnote, pg. 53 (Box W40)
      - Fact Checking -- Footnote, pg. 102 (Box W40)
      - Fact Checking - Legal Queries (2 folders) (Box W40)
      - Fact Checking - Levine (Box W40)
      - Fact Checking - Mental Health Reports (Box W40)
      - Fact Checking - Roxanne Pulitzer (Box W40)
      - Fact Checking - Scott v. McKinley (Box W40)
      - Fact Checking - Viguers Book - Retyped Pages (Box W40)
      - Footnotes (Box W40)
      - Introduction (2 folders) (Box W40)
      - Introduction (Box W40)
      - Journal - Notes and Drafts (2 folders) (Box W40)
      - Model Manuscript (Box W40)
      - Notes - Miscellaneous (Box W40)
      - Page Proofs, pg. 1-65 (Box W41)
      - Page Proofs, pg. 66-119 (Box W41)
      - Page Proofs, pg. 120-200 (Box W41)
      - Revisions, 1988, Jan. 30 (Box W41)
      - Revisions, 1988, June 2 (Box W41)
      - Revisions, 1988 (Box W41)
      - Surrogacy Overview (Box W41)
      - Titles (Box W41)
      - Typescripts - Miscellaneous (3 folders) (Box W41)